[Music]
hi
everyone this is Ravi welcome to trien
tosa Advanced
Training so this is our lesson 15 as
part of Advanced Training or it is a
lesson 30 as an overall trient TSA
automation tutorial
so in this lesson I'm going to talk
about a very important concept called
handling embedded controls inside the
table cells okay so how can we handle
the controls that are available in any
kind of table or a web table within the
page right so how can we handle while
automating your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive re
notifications whenever I publish more
videos so now let us jump onto the
system and see how can we handle
embedded controls in table cells okay so
now let me go to my trien tasa right so
this is my trient tasa so I want to
create a new exercise called let me
create a new
exercise I'll name this as
handling
embedded controls
in table okay so now first before we
start automating a test case let us
first understand what test case are we
going to automate okay so as you all
know we'll be moving to our web shop
demo webshop provided by tric centers
okay as we are doing in all the classes
okay okay so now let us navigate to
shopping cart okay under shopping cart
if I want to update the shopping cart by
remove removing one of the item from the
shopping cart how can we do that check
the checkbox under remove column right
you have a remove checkbox and then
click on update shopping cart correct so
now whatever the checkbox that we are
seeing here right this is actually part
of a web table it's a table under table
called shopping cart table we have a
column called remove under remove column
you have a checkboxes under products
column you have all the products that
you added under price column you have
price of each product and quantity of
each product and total of your each
product so now if I want to steer the
control that is inside the table which
is remove checkbox how can we do that
okay so now for that let me just jump
onto my trient toar and here let us go
to modules okay this is my module right
I want to scan the web table okay let us
click on scan and click on
application so what I'm going to do so I
want to scan the control within the
table right so remove checkbox so let me
do that okay so here I want to scan this
this is my application I want to scan
click on
scan and
now okay so now let me select select on
screen option okay select on screen if I
select this checkbox okay this is my
checkbox okay select this checkbox as
soon as you select this
checkbox I want to unselect this now let
us see more controls by clicking on the
filters to the towards right side okay
let's click on this towards right side
if you see here closely if You observe
closely let me expand this this remove
checkbox is under table called this one
right so that's why I want to add the
table also select
this and now I want to re name this
as
shopping
cart table okay but if you see your web
table is not uniquely identified so you
need to make sure your web table is
uniquely identified okay for that I'm
going to Simply click on make
unique so now you can see the orange
color is disappeared that means your web
table is now uniquely identified
what about this one this is your
checkbox if you see I have multiple
check boxes here is one checkbox let me
go further okay let me go further if you
see observe
closely these check boxes are
under table row if you see TR first row
has this checkbox product price total
second row again it has a checkbox
product total everything right so it's
basically the row of tables correct so
now you have a duplicates that's why the
checkbox is not uniquely identified that
is okay I just want to keep moving okay
I'm going to name this as
remove checkbox okay I'm name naming
this as remove checkbox and this
checkbox is not uniquely identified why
let's go and see
here how this checkbox is getting
identified by using
name called remove from cot and the tag
called input okay let me take a snip of
this one okay I want to just take snip
of this one so that I can use this in
further session okay let's take a snip
okay I want to just take a snip so your
remove checkbox is uniquely identified
by using name and tag okay I just took
the screenshot of that okay let's keep
like that okay so now I want to add
these two controls web table and your
remove one of the remove checkbox even
though it is not unic identified okay
let's save this I'm saving it and let's
close this okay so now let us go back to
trient tasa so this is the new module
that we added just now okay this is the
new module that we added okay so now I
want to create a test case now what
empty shopping card C text test case I
want to empty this shopping cart by
checking each item and click on update
shopping card check this item update the
shopping cart correct to handle this
update shopping cart button is
outside outside your web table but these
checkboxes are inside the table correct
so let's go back here let me create one
new test case called empty shopping
cart
empty
shopping card okay so now I want to drag
and drop the shopping card just now we
scanned okay drag this and drop
here so now let's just minimize this
modules little bit and let us focus on
test case now okay so if you see here
now your web table is
available okay and the web table
shopping cart is having a row and a cell
and this has a column and a cell but if
you see remove checkboxes outside the
table the outside the table now let us
say I want to directly check this
checkbox we'll see what happens okay
just true to check the checkbox you need
to select either true or false if you
select true that means it's going to
check the checkbox okay I selected true
now if I run the test case now okay it
it is going to fail let see why because
the remove checkbox is not uniquely
identified because you have a two remove
checkboxes with a name and ID or tag the
name and tag are same for both of them
now tasa will identify more than one
control here more than one checkbox so
that's why the test case is going to
fail let's see what happens
now so it is failed let's let's see the
result it's it should say tasa
identified more than one control right
let's go here and see here it says C it
says more than one control found for
Action remove check box so now how can
we handle this so now the way how can we
handle is we need to
somehow tie our
checkbox to the particular row let's
assume if I'm able to tie the checkbox
for a particular row so my first row has
this checkbox first I need to identify
the row uniquely and from that row I can
check the checkbox in the same way I
need to identify a row uniquely second
row and then you can check the check I
mean you can check the check box under
second row right so that means we need
to tie this remove checkbox to the
corresponding row cell either your first
row cell or is it second row cell that's
how you can uniquely identify so now how
can we do that it's very easy okay so
how what we going to do let's go back to
our module again okay let's go back to
modules again now if you see I want to
tie this remove checkbox to the row of
cell how simply drag drag this and drop
onto the row
cell so now you see your remove checkbox
is tied to a cell under particular row
right under a row basically within the
web table see now you have a row you
have a column under row under one of the
cell you have remove checkbox now it's
our duty to identify a unique row now
okay so what we are going to do here now
I want to steer a row that means I want
to handle I want to steer a control
which is checkbox under Row one so
that's why what I'm going to do for row
I'm going to select dollar one which
represents your first row of the table
excluding the
headers and now what is the column I
want to select the column remove I want
select let's select the column
remove okay so now if you see under
colum remove we already added a checkbox
called remove checkbox so now let us
select it as true in this
case so
now you are able to
identify a specific row and then once
you identify the unique row now you are
steering your remove checkbox correctly
now here my column I'm not asking to
verify it actually I want to select the
column right so you need to select the
column now if you run this test case
okay this one is already we removed
because if you see
here we moved our shopping cart remove
checkbox from here to here that's why
test case is showing as error so let me
delete this now okay because your remove
checkbox is not outside the table remove
checkbox is within the table see here
first
row and your remove checkbox and
everything now let us run this now okay
what it should do when I run this it
should check my first checkbox checkbox
which is under Row one okay simply right
click and
run right click and run
so if you see here now it should be able
to identify your checkbox even though
your checkbox is not uniquely identified
because we are arriving to the unique
row see it's got checked now that means
we are uniquely identifying the row and
then the corresponding checkbox okay
that means we are able to tie our
checkbox to particular row right row of
the cell so if you see here
successfully checked your
checkbox correct so
now let me do one more thing what if
your checkbox is not
scanned let's say I want to remove this
checkbox now okay from here let's remove
the checkbox totally so oh before you
remove the checkbox I want to delete
this particular test case okay let me
delete the test case okay let's delete
the test case case and now remove your
checkbox okay delete your checkbox now
what we have currently we have only
shopping cart we only scanned shopping
cart corresponding row and column so we
have not scanned your remove checkbox
right so how can you achieve same
function how can you steer remove
checkbox without scanning so there is a
way okay so all you need to do is so if
see let me bring the module here okay
let me bring the module to the full
screen what I'm going to do you need to
right click on the cell where you want
to add the control okay here under row
cell I want to add one technical okay I
want to add checkbox control create
embedded checkbox control just create
embedded checkbox control okay now I
have created a embedded checkbox control
and rename this as
remove checkbox remove checkbox okay so
I renamed it now under remove checkbox
now it is mandatory to know your
technical information of your remove
checkbox what is the technical
information the remove checkbox has a
technical property called name remove
from cart and and there is another
technical property called tag input okay
let us create those technical properties
manually what I'm going to do let's
expand this so if you see here these are
all the my
properties right click on remove
checkbox and expand this create
technical ID
parameter I'm going to name this as name
property it's name property right let's
see here let us see it's a name property
what is the property value remove from
cot I'm going to Simply write remove
from cot done what is another technical
property which is tag value input okay
let's add
tag another technical
property called tag and the value is
capital input okay so now
I'm able to add the control without
scanning okay let's go back here now
let's go back here now let's pull the
module again to
aside okay so let's go to test case so
if you see
here now I can simply drag this and drop
here okay so now
again let me select my row again Row
one we are performing the same thing
okay you are selecting your row select
action mode and here let me select
remove column under remove column I want
to select but not verify select and here
this is my
checkbox you can just simply type
true okay and this is input save this
now okay now let us run
this okay let us run this now what
happens we'll see right click
run so basically this time we have not
scanned the control instead we have
created the control okay and we have
defined our technical properties see
it's successful so now one more quick
update I want to give you okay
okay so we defined all the properties
manually and now you are able to steer
the control correct but but if You
observe closely here in the
table we have checkbox control only one
checkbox control right you don't have
for a particular row you have only one
checkbox do am I finding any other
checkboxes in any other cells no I have
only one checkbox for every each and row
so that means I need not to define the
properties at all technical properties
at all so what I'm going to do I'm going
to remove this one delete the technical
property name delete the technical
property tag and save this because my
business Type R control type is checkbox
and I have only one checkbox control
type for each row so that's why I need
mean not to Define technical properties
if you have multiple checkboxes within
the row you need to Define let's see
when I remove the technical properties
can I run this now we removed the
technical properties we save now this
remove checkbox does not have your
technical properties now okay let me run
this simply this time what I'm going to
do I'm going to specify row number two
that means I'm asking to check the row
number two okay simply right click and
run
now so I'm running this now without the
technical properties of your remove
checkbox because you have only one
checkbox within the
row see now without your technical
properties also you are able to check
the checkbox right so hope you all
understand it is really very very
important concept guys how can you steer
the controls within the table
you can steer the control here edit box
right whatever the way we steer the
control of checkbox you can also steer
the control of edit boxes right hope you
all understand the different ways of
handling controls of your row cell
controls that are available in
particular row under a particular cell
so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank
[Music]
you